[
    {
        "id":"1",
        "question":"What is CSS?",
        "options":[
            "CSS is a style sheet language",
            "CSS is designed to separate the presentation and content, including layout, colors, and fonts",
            "CSS is the language used to style the HTML documents",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        "id":"2",
        "question":"Which of the following tag is used to embed CSS in html page?",
        "options":[
            "<css>",
            "<!DOCTYPE html>",
            "<script>",
            "<style>"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"<style>"

    },
    {
        "id":"3",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS selectors are used to specify a group of elements?",
        "options":[
            "tag",
            "id",
            "class",
            "both class and tag"
        ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"class"

    },
    {
        "id":"4",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS framework is used to create a responsive design?",
        "options":[
            "django",
            "rails",
            "larawell",
            "bootstrap"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"bootstrap"

    },
    {
        "id":"5",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS selector is used to specify a rule to bind a particular unique element?",
        "options":[
            "tag", 
            "id", 
            "class",
            "both class and tag"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"id"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"6",
        "question":"Which of the following type of HTML tag is used to define an internal style sheet?",
        "options":["<script>", "<link>", "<class>", "<style>"],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"<style>"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"7",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS property is used to make the text bold?",
        "options":[
            "text-decoration: bold", 
            "font-weight: bold", 
            "font-style: bold",
            "text-align: bold"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"font-weight: bold"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"8",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS style property is used to specify an italic text?",
        "options":[
            "style", 
            "font", 
            "font-style",
            "@font-face"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"font-style"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"9",
        "question":"What will be the output of following CSS code snippet?",
        "options":[
            "color: red, text-decoration: underline works", 
            "only font-style: italic works", 
            "color: red, text-decoration: underline and font-style: italic all works",
            "text-decoration: underline and font-style: italic works"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "code":"h1 {color: red text-decoration: underline; font-style: italic;}",
        "ans_desc":"only font-style: italic works"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"10",
        "question":"Which of the following are the CSS Extension Prefixes for Webkit?",
        "options":[
            "-chrome", 
            "-web", 
            "-o-",
            "-webkit"
            ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"-webkit"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"11",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax to link an external style sheet in the HTML file?",
        "options":[
            "<link rel=”stylesheet” href=”style.css” />", 
            "<link rel=”stylesheet” src=”style.css” />", 
            "<style rel=”stylesheet” src=”style.css” />",
            "<style rel=”stylesheet” link=”style.css” />"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"<link rel=”stylesheet” href=”style.css” />"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"12",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS property can be used to set the image as a border instead of the border style?",
        "options":[
            "background-image-source", 
            "background-image", 
            "border-image-source",
            "border-image"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"border-image-source"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"13",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS property defines the different properties of all four sides of an element's border in a single declaration?",
        "options":[
            "border-collapse", 
            "border-width", 
            "padding",
            "border"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"border-width"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"14",
        "question":"Which of the following CSS selector selects the elements that are checked?",
        "options":[
            ":checked", 
            "E ~ F", 
            "::after",
            "none of the mentioned"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":":checked"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"15",
        "question":"Which of the following values are accepted by the float Property?",
        "options":[
            "left", 
            "right", 
            "none",
            "all of the mentioned"
            ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"all of the mentioned"

        
    }
   

    

]